I think we stopped at 3:32.
I'm
fine.  Alright.  Well, no, no, I have
no problem starting there.
Okay.  Well, lady, who is
she talking to?  for
$0.  He's talking to the
devil.  The misunderstanding.   He's
speaking with a misunderstanding.  By the
way, I heard that you guys had
finished some
images, the images for Flot, and I
think I'll be able to see them
tomorrow.  Alright.  From each house.  And I
heard they did very well, but I
'll judge tomorrow.
Okay.  Well, she calls him arrogant.  You
think you're a master, but you're not a
master.  You're lacking it, aren't you?  We already
covered that.  You don't have good qualities and you
don't have the things that give you those
good qualities.
Meditation.  Let's start with 332.
332.
You say that nothing depends on
anything.  You say that things are not
changeable, things are not changeable.
You say that things have an end
and that things are solid, he said that
.  The bad part of your
mind thinks that nothing will
change.  Not directly.  Very good
answer.  someone, some person on
this
side.  Correct.  Of course
you understand that things change, like, I do
n't know, you get hungry after eating
lunch and they make you stay in these
long classes and you get hungrier and hungrier
.  Your hunger changes.  Nobody can
say that things don't
change.  Ignorance doesn't mean
things don't change.  He never said that.
Why is he accusing him of this?
My teacher in the Management course, if a
person gave all the answers, he
would say, "Did you choose him to answer
all the
questions?"  Yes, they did.
Well, if things don't come from your
own seeds, if things don't come
from your seeds, then they wouldn't
change in your mind. If you think
things come from the outside in
, for $00 the word in Tibetan I did
n't
hear it.  In this country you have
more votes, but you still don't become
president, even if you have the largest
majority of the votes.
Den.  It's
Dunen,
not the person who thinks everything
comes from
outside, that doesn't mean he's your
student.   The dollar sign (
$) means that it comes from the object
towards the eye.  Tom means that's
how you see things.  So, what is
an area?
Aria means someone who has touched
the path of the diamond directly,
has had direct perception of
the swing. Yung is the opposite, it is not
an area.  They think the world comes
from here to here, they don't understand that the
world is this
way.  Which leads me to the
next
question.  How is my money doing?  How
is my cash balance?  I can't trust
you.  Oh no, I can trust you.  This
is easy money.  If your family asks you,
"Why did you take a week off to go
to [unclear]?" you tell them, "Well, I earned more
money than if I stayed to
work."  Here's the question.
Ready?  How many
times does the diamond cutter's sutra
mention the diamond?
Raise your
hand.
Zero.
Yse.  What I'm trying to
say is,
okay, Cintian, the director
of this place for 12 years, you can answer
this question for more money.  What is
the Sanskrit word for diamond?  And what is
the related English word?
The word in Sanskrit
means instrument of
power.
Vegetables.  Vegetables.  Yes. Very
good.  Why did people in
ancient times agree with
my wife and say that
vegetables make you very powerful,
vegetables make you very strong?
Well, that was in ancient times, they do
n't say that anymore.  Well,
anyway, any time
you see a diamond, any time you
see someone talking about diamonds,
you have to ask, why are they
all talking about diamonds now?
Are you in a diamond class?  The
path of the diamond signifies a
suspicious person.  Ah, the Buddha is trying to
send me a message.  Someone
asks you, why do they call him the
carrier?
The cut diamond day is a
message.  Okay.  That is one
answer from the diamond path.  The
diamond in the cutter in the
diamond cutter's super
signifies something in the diamond's path
.  It means that if you're not
on the diamond path, you're supposed to
not.  If you're in a
diamond class, then of course
you answer.  Of course, it's a
message.  Well,
anyway, if someone could give me, I don't
know, it's a lot of money, but let's
answer one question
without money.
Okay.  She accuses the devil of
believing that nothing changes.  He believes that.  She
says, "You think nothing changes."
Why would she say that?
Say it into the microphone only for your
teacher,
not to win
money.
[Music]
May I?  There are certain people who have to
pay the teacher $100 in order to get
an answer.
No. Okay.  Okay.  Don't forget the
question.  The question is, why does the
angel
accuse misunderstanding?  Why does he
tell her that you think nothing changes?  Of
course he doesn't think that.  You and I, we
lived for many years without ever having
touched the diamond path, perhaps
.  So why?  Why do
we believe that nothing changes?  Because we can
see that things change minute by
minute, every moment.  She is
accusing the devil of falling into
extremes, of falling into one of the
extremes.  In this view, if you think
that things have
self-existence, then the result of
that belief has to be that things
do not change.  And therefore, if he says
that things are the way they are, you have to
believe that there is some kind of belief
that it doesn't change.  If you believe that things
come from outside and I ask you, do
you think that things will never change?  No,
of course I know that's not the case, but
of course it's not like that.  If things
exist from their own lips, they
cannot change.  They would never change.  They
couldn't change.  If it doesn't
come from your seeds, what is a
seed?  Why do things change?
Because your
seeds change.  When
the seed creates the tree, the
seed is no longer there.  The
seed gave energy to the tree, and the
tree used the energy to grow, and
then the tree
died.  If things come from your
seeds, then they can be
impermanent, they can die.  But if they don't
come from your seeds, then
why would they need to change?
If they come from outside this situation, what would make them
change?  So she's
accusing him.  You are the person
he believes nothing ever changes.  And he says, "No,
I never said that."  Yes, but you think about it.
You believe it.  Did you understand correctly?  Okay.  Very
good.  And then he accuses her of not having
any, of not having any friends.
He accuses her of not having any friends.  He
accuses her of being a
lonely person.  He accuses her of never coming
home.  Where is home?  Where is the house?
In the human mind.  You're never there.
Like maybe once a year
when you're in the middle of class and
you think about emptiness, and the rest
of the time you're just worried about
how annoying people are.  Do you see what I
mean?  Then, he accuses her
of being a loner, of
having no friends, of not even coming
home to be with her husband.  And
what does she say?  It's not me who doesn't have
friends, it's you who doesn't have friends.
Because?
Because all the friends you think you have don't
even
exist.  The next time you get
into a conflict with your partner, you can
try
this.  Probably nothing else will get
confused.  If things don't come from
you, then they can't exist.  First, they
cannot change.
And number two, they couldn't exist just any old
way.  You know, the two
husbands in the kitchen, you
know him.  The husband who is
hurting you, even though you didn't do
anything, there is no such
thing.  I didn't do
anything.  We mean, where is it?
Where?  When they need it.  It's good.   I
did nothing.
I think he should use it at home.
Don't
tell him [Music].  The wife says, "My husband
started yelling at me, but I didn't do anything.
In this system, if the pen comes from
you, then the husband comes from you.
The husband is saying something to you that
comes from
you, and then you're going to get
upset. If you understand where it comes from,
you can change it. If you don't understand,
then it will last for 100 years and it doesn't
exist. It's something that's going to last
forever, but it doesn't even exist. Something
wonderful,
right? Then, you know, he says to
her, 'You don't have any
friends.' And she
says, 'I am, I have friends.'"  Everyone
is my friend.  Don't say I don't have
friends.  Everyone in the world is my
friend.  I get along well with everyone.
Who is speaking?  Yes, the angel who
understands the
seeds.  Everyone, everyone, everyone in
the world is my friend.  I love everyone and
everyone loves me because I am real,
because I come from seeds.  I have
true relationships that come
from seeds.
When I enter into a relationship, I take
care of it
by honoring the relationships of
others.  I don't yell at my husband, I
only honor the relationship, I keep
my promises and I force him to keep
his.  Did you understand?  Very
interesting.  Therefore, I get along
with everyone, which
means that if
you understand that things come from
seeds, you can be close to
everything, because that's what's real, that's the
real world, that's the only
real world.   Did
you understand?  It's not that feathers come
from seeds, but that everything comes from
seeds.  And if you don't understand that, you're
living in a place that isn't real.   You
're living in a place that doesn't
even exist, so you're a little
crazy, which is why 8 billion people
are apparently crazy or maybe
Buddhas.  Well, I didn't say they were, but
I also didn't say they weren't.
Okay.  Then what she says is, she's into
the topic of
friendship and she has the idea that
people are naturally friendly.  Everyone
is close to me because they
depend on me.  We depend on them, they
depend on me.  How is it that the world
depends on me?  Of course, my
seeds, the world depends on me.  Don't
tell me I don't have
friends.  The next time your husband
tells you that you don't have any friends, you say,
"I have many friends. It all depends on me
because my mind is creating
everything."  Now, here's a
$100 question.  Everyone
[Music]
is.  Okay.
Come on.  He says, "You're a loner,
you're a loser, you have no friends. You only
come to mind once a year when
you go to Diamond for five
minutes, and mostly you're out there
and you have no friends." He's
accusing her of that. She says, "No, no, I
am. I have friends, and everyone is
my friend." And he says, "Why?"  "What?"
And she says to him, "Everyone is my
friend.  "Why do they come from me?"
Okay. The feather and everything else comes
from me, therefore, they love me
, they are my friends. Got it?
Now, that's called
dependence,
dependency. But there's a deeper idea
. Do you want to go into that
? It's interdependence. I
'll make it
simple. The feather depends on your
seeds. Do you
want it simple, or to be simple? No.
How simple? Okay. The feather depends
on your seeds. Therefore, the feather
is your
friend. Sorry, you are the feather's friend
because without you, the feather wouldn't
be there, or the friend wouldn't be
there.
But, but it's also
your friend. The feather is also your
friend.
It's interdependence. It's not just
originating dependence, it's
original interdependence. The tree depends, look, I
'll make it simple. The tree
depends on the seed, and the seed
depends on the tree. But how can you
do that if the tree came after the
seed?
Your mind created the seed, and then
the tree, and your mind creates it as
cause and
effect.  I'm going to refine this a little.
Okay. The seed creates the tree,
obviously, but the tree also creates
the seed because you can't
call it
the cause of the tree because the tree already
existed.
Thank you very much. Your seeds create the feather,
but your feather created the seeds of the
feather.
Right, your seeds create the feather, but
the feather creates the seeds of the
feather. That's
mutually dependent reality. Both of
both ways. Everyone
is going around doing this. I created the
feather, and I created the feather. But the feather created your
seeds because there can't be seeds
until there is
something. The Diamond Way, the
Diamond Way of Diamond
Mountain. All feathers are seeds,
and everyone knows the secret.
Okay. A normal DC student thinks,
"Everything comes from seeds."  Everything
comes from
seeds.  Diamond Mount, a
diamond path, master, a master of the
five
houses.  The pen comes from
me.  "The feather comes from my seeds."
Do you understand? It's his new
[Music]
mudra. It's a new
mudra. I created the
feather. The feather comes from my seeds, and
my seeds are seeds because of the
feather. When you think about
dependent origination, it's
from both sides. That's deeper. They do
n't usually teach it.
People don't usually teach it, but it's
true. But it's true, even up to
World. What's the ancestral example
of the seed thing?
The
triangle part, the
spheres. Ah, the
spheres.
In the
ancestral teachings, they talk about it as the example of
the spheres. In ancient warfare, right?
Ah, not spears, not spheres, sorry.
At the beginning of the spear, they had a
shaft, and then they had a
metal point.
So, even in ancient
warfare, they
needed time.
So, in warfare, they would say, "Okay,
let's take a break for
lunch." And then everyone would
go back to their  They'd set up camp and start
the game, and they'd start
cooking, and
then there wasn't a good fighter, so
no one would put their spear on the ground because
then the point would rust. So they
always stack the spears like this,
and they lean on each other, and it takes
two people to put them like this because they
have to lean on each other.
What's
the point? The feather depends on the seed,
and the seed depends on the feather. It's
mutual. It's a mutual interdependence. You
have to remember
that. Your husband comes from you, but
you also come from your
husband because there is no you without your husband
coming from
you.
Okay. And by the
way, when you have a problem, when you're
upset with another person, you're doing
something wrong with this relationship, something is
n't right, of course it's a
problem if you think that the
other person doesn't come from you, but you
also have to understand that you
come from him.
If you're always accusing
someone, you're just making things worse
because it goes both
ways. It's really true because
the tree defines the
seed. If the other
person...  That you're in a relationship
is wrong, then it's proof that
you're wrong. And that's difficult. That's
complicated. If someone tells you that all
the idiots in your life come from
you, they're right. And then
you say, because it's a reflection, because it's
a reflection of you. You say, and they
define you. No, how
cool.
[Music]
Okay. Everyone knows I want to
study the
Diamond Way. I don't want philosophy. If
you want philosophy, I'd train a
12-
year-old. I just want the Diamond Way
. I
only want the Diamond Way.
Okay, you
understand.
Okay. So, what she's
arguing about, what's going on
here, you have to be in it, you have to
get into the argument. The angel
is arguing with the devil, and he's
saying, "You're a loser."   You
come home, you're always
alone, you come home once a year, I
see you once a
year, you make me think that for 5 minutes
my husband can be coming from
you, then you forget, but you're never
here.  Why should I listen to you?
You're a lonely person, and she
says, "I'm not lonely, you're the one who
's lonely. Everyone is my
friend. Everyone who lives on this
planet is my friend, because they are
the tree and I am the
seed. They make me, they create
who I am. It's
very you, feather kids, go
to DC.
You, you seed kids, the
feather creates your
seeds. So thank the
feather. Thank you, feather." And the feather
says to you, "No, thank
you."  If it weren't for your seeds, I wouldn't
be here." Then you have to
say, "But without you, I wouldn't have
a seed either because there wouldn't be any
seeds because there wouldn't be anything." Do
you understand? Dependence, dependence,
origination, dependent,
dependent, is two-way,
which means she's never
alone and she
knows it. If you understand
dependence, then you're a deep
friend to every other person on
this
planet and on another planet too, but I do
n't want you to get carried away. I'm
going to repeat it. If
you really understand the
pen, then you're
automatically connected to every other person on this planet. If
you understand the pen, everyone in
the world is your friend because they
depend on each other. Don't tell me
I'm crazy because I only get to my
brain once a year. I
agree, but all day long I'm being
friends with everyone and you're not. Okay.
Did you get it? Yes, he doesn't. Who is he?
Yes. Ignorance, or whatever you call it,
misunderstanding.
[Music]
Good. Then she continues or she goes to
a  A very sexy list. She's
bragging now. You're the loser.
Who? Ignorance. You're the
lonely one. You sit there all alone.
I have friends. I have so many
friends. You wouldn't even realize it, you wouldn't
even imagine it. And he says,
"Oh, yeah, like who?" And then she
starts, "Here's a list of my
friends." Okay. And here it
goes, like the sun rises, like the moon rises.
The sky and the moon are my friends. Is
n't that wonderful?
Yes. The directions of my body, this
me, or
this one, depend on me. Do you get it now?
She's bragging about how many friends she
has. He accused her of
not having friends because she was a
loser. And she says to him, "I am a
loser."  I have friends in
high places.  Where?  The sun and the moon.
And I have the east and the
west.  I have day and
night, they are my friends, do
you understand?
And winter, summer, autumn, the four
seasons and spring are my
friends.  The fact that it
rains makes the flowers and
fruit grow.  It comes from me.  He's already
bragging about how many friends he
has.  They are all my friends.  Now,
Stanley for
$100 and then you'll be able to buy another
statue.  Well, part of a statue.
He's not going to answer in every
way, so that's
okay.  This is the discussion of
borders.  She's really talking
about borders.  He's saying, "My
friends are the border between day and
night. My friends are the border between
east and west, between summer and
winter, between the
ancient Sanskrit, summit.
Oh, I told you this is a
50-question answer. And what is the Tibetan for
summit? Sam.
There are two words you have to
learn. The Tibetan is Sam ts, the
Manskrit of Sam, that's a long i.
Sima, sima. And sima means
border and it comes into Spanish as
the seam, like the stitching
here. The
seam where they join the
fabric to make something. That's what in
Spanish is called the seam, which comes
from
[Music]
summit. Sutra comes from
estro. What does sima mean?
Uh, that became the
border. Sa, it became the
border and it's extremely important for
the retreat center. It's a very
important thing for a retreat center.
Every time we do a retreat, a
silent retreat, a serious retreat,
we create a border. Well,
we create
two."  David knows both.
He says, "How much
money?" Two borders at
least.
Yeah, you know, one runs up the mountain and
puts a stick up and it's called a
saint. Or you can put a piece of paper on your
door or you have to do both. That's
like an inner circle. There are more
circles, but we're not going to talk about
these saints. This is... Yes, ma. Sima
means, please repeat, summit is a
long i.
Summit means the border between... and I
was telling the people in
Dun when I take a 3-year retirement, he and... they
remember, I was in the
car, I was finishing the Diamond
Cutter Supra business book in
the car and we got to the
border of the retirement and I said to her,
"Hold on."
And then I handed her the
manuscript to give to the
publisher. And then we parked,
we walked over and I
turned around and there's a... it's a
cattle gate and I opened it and said,
"Okay, I'm not going to... I'm not going to come out of this
gate for 3 years." It's a very... feeling
weird. You know it. It says, "3 years.
You have a question about whether to release the gate or
not.  And then I let her go.  I said, "Okay, I'm not
going to leave this fence, this fence for 3
years and I didn't
."  And very strange things happen
.  I told them a story about
when I broke a tooth and one of
the other people were retired.  I said, "No,
I have to go to town, I have to go to
a dentist."  And they said to me, "Haven't
you ever heard of super glue?"
I said to them, "What?"  "Put on some super glue,
this with the
crazy stuff." But the tooth's gone,
half of it is. No, no, no. We're
going to fill it with the crazy stuff. And I
said, "Okay, well, let's try it."
So I didn't break the summit, I didn't cross the
summit for three years, three times, three days.
So we have this idea in the
angel and
devil talk about the summit. But here the summit
is, what is the line between the sun and the
moon? What is the line between the feather and
the seeds? What is the line between
east and west? We had a project before
in Mexico on the other side of the border
in
Douglas, in Agua Prieta.
We tried to write Tibetan there. All
the computers were stolen
. We actually
did it. And I said, "Ah, I have to go
there, I have to do something." And so
I crossed the border to talk to the
workers and I said, "Wait a
minute." I said to the police,
"Can I do one thing?" And the policeman
said,  "That?  Because he doesn't trust you at
all." And I said, "Just for
fun, I want to put one foot in the
United States and one foot in
Mexico and see how it
feels." And I was
like, I was standing there
looking at the
border and I said, "You know what?"  It feels
exactly the same.  I feel nothing.  I don't
feel like there are any borders.  I don't see
any border.  It's just land.
It's desert, it's really just land and I
can't really see, but it's a
karmic line.  The people on this side, many
people on this side are
hungry and at six feet, 2 meters, people
have too much food and everyone is
dying from being fat, from obesity.
So these people are hungry and
they are dying.  So,
who created that border?
It's like a politician who created that
border.  It is your seeds that
created that border.  So what he's
saying is that borders belong
to my
friends.  The border between you and other
people, the border between your eye and the
pen, the border between you and
me, all come from seeds.  The
borders come from the seeds of the summit;
they come from your seeds.  Did you understand?
She's not just saying, you know?  The
sun and moon come from me, the east and
west come from me, day and night
come from me, winter and summer
come from me.  She's not saying that.
She is saying, "You are the creator
of the lines. You are the one who creates those
lines."  Incidentally
, if everyone understood
this, then a very
strange language would develop.  David and I
went to Tom Juan so that David could have
a conference so that David could
translate from Chinese to
English.  And then, you
know, you'd have to change all
human languages.  All
languages ​​are based on
incorrect perceptions.  The word "
you and I" is a
mistake.  It's not about whether you're a good person.
You should think of me as I think of you, of me
as you think of me.  That's not true.  That's
incorrect.  There shouldn't be a you and there
shouldn't be an I.
Should we eat lunch or
shouldn't we eat
lunch?  It doesn't matter where the
border is.   Did
you understand?  I am you.  And you are me.
Therefore, if you understand this,
then the partner in your mind can
tell you, "You have no friends."
You might say, "No, you don't
understand. I'm the only one who's
friends with everyone."  The angel says,
"You are the loser. You are the
lonely one, you are the one without
friends. You don't realize that you cannot
exist without other people. You
are other people."  Did you understand?
It is very powerful.  This is very powerful.   That's why it
took us about 10 years to
get to this point.  And we've only
written one
verse.  Now, when you think about
wisdom, it says, understanding,
understanding the seeds, understanding the
pen, it says, "I have good friends and you don't
even know where the
friends are.
I have such good friends that they are
me. They are me. Don't tell me I don't have
friends. It's true that I don't have
friends. I am my friends and they are
me. And that's how it is. And that's how close we
are. And if you understand this, then
your life is wonderful. Your life is all,
every day is very fun.
Every day is very fun.
Recognizing that you are other
people is fun all
day long, not
endlessly. You can be silly
all
day. Good.
Okay. Really, and that's very fun.
Even if all this is philosophy, I don't
care. If you want to have fun all
day, every day, that's
fun. That's really fun.
Only, you're not just going to have fun
on your birthday, because that's only
once a
year. Maybe, what is a
deep wisdom of
Gesela? Yes, someone said to me, "How many
students do you want?" And I  I said,
"365 with different
birthdays.  My wife says, "Don't eat
the dessert. It's someone's birthday."   I
need to eat
dessert.  Good.  So the borders
come from you.  All borders
originate from you.  Perhaps they are not so
useful and are directly related
to retirement.  Because the word for
retreat in the ancient
sacred or sanitary language is not border and
means keeping yourself within the
border.  That's a different border.
That means that sometimes you
can think more clearly if you're not
around hundreds of people, if you have
a family, if you
work, if you have a normal life, that's
fine.  Other people are
wonderful.  Being with other people
is very nice, but sometimes
being alone in your retreat, in your
retreat cabin, is wonderful.  And then
when you come out, I don't know, John Brady, I...
something happened to me in retirement.  I
remember looking out the window.  I
remember perfectly looking out the window
and saying, "This isn't
fun being here for 1,000 days. I didn't have a
toilet, I didn't have any water, I did
n't have electricity. I was in the
desert and I was thinking, this
isn't fun.
Why? Because there's no one to
help me. There's no one to help, and I can't have the
fun of helping someone. I
felt very lonely,
and the retreat is great, but I don't
have the opportunity to cook for
anyone, I don't have the opportunity to
greet anyone or talk to anyone, I do
n't have the opportunity to serve
anyone. So one of the reasons for
going on retreat—and you're going to do
a deep retreat—for four
days,
you're going to start missing
people. The first day is wonderful.
Oh, I finally get rid of this person
who talks all day.
And then, around day three, it's like, oh, I
miss them, and you're going to feel a little
lonely, and those are the moments
to
think about being a Bodhisattva.
And when you're on a deep retreat
for a long time, you
On your own, you'll be able to understand how much
you need other people and how
fun and sweet it is to have other
people to
serve. It doesn't matter if they're good
people or bad people. Serving
bad people is more fun than serving
good people. It's an art form,
an advanced art form.
Then she goes into the
darkness, how much time do we have
left? And then she goes into the
darkness. It's like, and it's a little bit
dark. Suddenly she turns around and
goes somewhere else
. I'm still on verse 337,
guys.
She says, "There's a
boundary
between spring, fall, summer, and
winter." And then she says, "There's a
boundary called living and dead." And
then she starts—she goes into the
darkness—and everyone's like,
yeah.
She says, "There's another
boundary, and it's called life and death."
And then she says, "There are other
divisions."  You may be
sick or you may be in active agony, you
may be suffering at Diamond
Mountain in the same week as the
excessive heat or the
excessive cold.  As for the bathrooms, that's
for the heat.  Well, this hunger in
one hand,
silk and all the rest.  So she is
suddenly making a
transition to other frontiers between
pain, between aging, death, she
is going to the four truths of
Mary, to the four truths of
suffering.  And he said, "I also created
the
lines between the four truths. I
created the lines between pain and the
cause of pain. I created the line between
nirvana and the causes and the path. I
created those lines. I created Amrim. I
created those lines. You did it between
life and
death. If you understand that those lines
come from you, then you can
change them. If you don't
understand that they come from you, you won't be
able to change them. Okay.
If you understand where the peak is—what
is that? The boundary, where
the boundaries come from—you can change the
boundaries between life and death.
Okay. It's a kind of tantra. I can
add whatever I
want. Se and I are working on a
special project about helping people with
the second half of their lives.
What are you going to do in the second half of
your life? This kind of thing. We're
developing an idea. And
then I was teaching something like that
to people at TSU, at the
university, and someone said to me,
"M, so..."  "Are you teaching the
second half of life?" And I said,
"No, I'm teaching the first half of what comes next
." And they said, "Like,
like?" And I said, I'm not interested
in teaching you how to
grow old and get
kidney disease and die. To me, that doesn't sound very
interesting. What I'm teaching you
is the next two halves of your
life. What happens after what
comes next? How do
you transcend? It's not how to age
gracefully. I don't know, don't
forget to stretch because maybe you wo
n't be able to walk or something
. That's only the first half.
The second half is what happens
after. If you start a new project
when you're 40, that
's the first half of your new life.
And then we have to master the art of
the second half, which is
after you die. So do
n't think of life as the first
half and the second half. Don't
think like that. The second half of your life
is the first half.
Okay? Then what
happens? You die. And then you have another
half.
And if you study well, if you learn how to make
the retreat well, if you study the
diamond path well, it's
amazing fun. It's wonderful, it's
super cute. Do you know what color
the sky is going to be in my next life?
Peach. It's the only one that's better than
blue.
Imagine that you could be
planting or planning your next
childhood, your next
teenage years. Imagine that you can be
planting them now. So that's what
we're talking about. And you can say Gesela
is crazy or he knows
something. And it doesn't matter to me. I don't
care what you think, that you think
I'm crazy, I don't care. If you
want to give $100, that's fine. Maybe
I'm crazy or maybe I know
something. It's possible. We have to say
that either he knows something or maybe he does
or maybe he doesn't. Okay. Good. Well,
either way, I can't
wait. I want to  See you
in the next world.